5. Steve Jobs Take a quick look around you. Is someone typing
on a Mac, listening to an iPod, calling on an iPhone, using an iPad? Do you buy music
from iTunes? Have you seen Toy Story 3 or any other movie by Pixar? Amazingly, we have
one person to thank for all these innovations, Steve Jobs.
Steve and Paul Jobs was born in California in 1955 and adopted by Paul and Clara Jobs.
He became interested in computers in high school, going to after-school lectures at
the computer company Hewlett-Packard. He enrolled at Reed College in Oregon. Though he went
to a variety of classes, he never graduated. Instead, he moved back to California and began
working at Atari, the video game company. He also started working on his own computer
projects with Steve Wozniak. Jobs and Wozniak, along with Ronald Wayne, founded Apple, named
after Jobs' favorite fruit, in 1976. Apple changed the way people thought about computers.
The company made them small, easy to use, and accessible to normal people.
The Macintosh computer was launched in 1984, but sales slowed in 1985, and Jobs was pushed
out of his own company. After leaving Apple, Jobs founded Next Incorporated. The company
decided to develop both computer hardware and software. In 1986, he bought the company
that would end up being called Pixar. It paired with Disney to make computer-animated
movies. The first was Toy Story, a huge success. In 1996, Apple bought Next, and Jobs returned
to his original company. He cut programs and Jobs, but he also helped make Apple products
more beloved than ever. Apple has been on a roll ever since, creating elegant, fast,
computer-friendly products that reflect the vision of Steve Jobs.